Guide to the Vice President and Secretary Administrative Records 1925-1965 RG 4.0.1
New York University Libraries, Publisher
- Series III: Law Center Campaign
  - Law Campaign - Publicity, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Law Campaign - Publicity, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Law Campaign - General Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Law Campaign - Save Washington Square Movement, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Law Campaign - Law Building Site, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - File Copies of Law Building, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Files copies of Law Campaign Printed Matter, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Files copies of Law Campaign Printed Matter, 1945-1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Save Washington Square (Petitions), undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Plan for Law Center, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Series IV: New York University; Bellevue Medical Center Campaign
  - Administrative Series
    - Bellevue Medical Center: General Correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bellevue Medical Center: Organization of, 1949; , 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bellevue Medical Center: Salmon, Edwin A., Director of, 1944-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Blueprints, 1944-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Completed Phases: Hall of Residence Thank You Notes, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Construction Program, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Dentistry: Relation to Medical Center Plans, 1944-1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Direction: Medical Center Campaign, 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Director, Campaign: Correspondence with, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - General Correspondence, 1944-1948 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
    - H.I.P.: Relation to Medical Center, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hospital Administrator, Search for, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - To HOV from POB, Certain material for files in view of current developments, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Land Acquisition, 1944-1947 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Land Acquisition; Condemnation Proceedings, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Medical Center Campaign: Early Meetings and Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Meetings and Events, Calendars of, 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Mission of A Medical School, 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 0'Dwyer, William, Mayor. Correspondence with, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Operating Plans and Goals, 1945-1948 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Organization Charts, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Pathology Agreement, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Publicity, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B: Fundraising
    - Alumni Hall Fund, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Contributions: Medical Center Campaign, 1945-1949 (Box 2, Folder 11-13)
    - Dinner; First,October 21, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Dinner: Medicine's New Role in Industry, Sept. 30, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Dinner: Mr. R. H. Kress April 30, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Dinner: Mr. Richard L. Lawrence Sept. 27, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Dinners, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Doctors Orchestral Society Benefit, May 16, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Firms contacted by Campaign, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - The Forgotten Causality, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Foundations, 1944-1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - General Fundraising, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Institute of Cardiovascular-Renal Disease: Fundraising, 1945-1950 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
    - Investment of Business (pamphlet), 1946 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Luncheon: Mr. Richard L. Lawrence, October 17, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Luncheons and Dinners, 1944; , 1947-1950 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Medical Residence Hall, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Show of Shows, October 20, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Weekly Reports, 1945-1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Subseries C: Committees and Divisions
    - Advisory Committee on Public Information, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Central Committee, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Campaign Leaders: Agendas and Minutes, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Commerce and Industry Division, 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Committee of Seventy-Five: Declinations, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Committee of Seventy-Five: First Meeting, May 21, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Committee of Seventy-Five: Membership Drive, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Committee of Seventy-Five-Foundation, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Committees and Divisions Personal, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and Lists of Individuals asked to become Members of the Various Committees, 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Executive Committee Meetings, Notices, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Medical Alumni Division, 1946-1948 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Operating Committee, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Parents Association Division, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Planning Committee, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Special Projects Committee, 1947-1950 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Strategy Group: Meeting Notices, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Steering Committee: Faculty Planning Committee, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Steering Committee: Minutes, Agendas, Notices, 1945-1950 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Top Gifts Committee, 1947-1950 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - University Council, 1944-1947 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - University Council on Medicine and Dentistry, Sub-committee of, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Women's Division: Correspondence with, 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Photocopied Originals (newspaper clippings), undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Duplicates, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Post-Graduate Medical School, 1947-1949 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - School of Medicine, 1935; , 1942; , 1953 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Series V: Korean War Materials
  - Questionnaires requesting inventory of human resources, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Questionnaires requesting inventory of facilities, 1949-1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Association of Colleges and Universities of the State of New York, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Office of Education, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The University of the State of New York, State Education Department, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Philadelphia Forum Bulletin, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Form Letters, Copies of questionnaires, Memorandums on procedure, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Army Advisory Committee, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Department of Defense Office of Public Information, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Secretary of Defense, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Federal Security Agency, Defense Information Bulletin, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - National Education Association, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Naval Reservist, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Reserve Officers Training Corps, Air Force Branch at Washington Square, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Reserve Officers Training Corps, Program and Policies, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Selective Service System, Memorandums and correspondence, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Committee on Selective Service, 1948-1952 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Articles on the draft and recall of reserves, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - New York University Faculty Deferments, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Veterans Readjustment Assistance Act, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Colonel John N. Andrews, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - American Council on Education, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Council on Education, Higher Education and National Affairs, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - American Council on Education, Higher Education and National Affairs, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - American Council on Education, Higher Education and National Affairs, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Air Raid Precautions, 1950-1953 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Civilian Defense Lecture Program at New York University, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Association of Colleges and Universities of the State of New York, Committees on Manpower and Acceleration, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Statements on Manpower, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Educational Acceleration, Manpower and Mobilization, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Mobilization Planning and the National Defense (Senate Document), 1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
Related Material at the New York University Archives
(RG 3.0) Office of the Chancellor/President
(RG 3.0.4) Elmer Ellsworth Brown Administrative Records
(RG 3.0.5) Harry Woodburn Chase Administrative Reocrds
(RG 3.0.6) Presidential Administrative Subject File, 1951-1965
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.